I started juggling a long time ago,
لقد بدأت في رمي الكرات منذ زمن بعيد,
but long before that, I was a golfer, and that's what I was, a golfer.
ولكن قبل ذلك كنت لاعب غولف, هذا ما كنت عليه
And as a golfer and as a kid,
وكـ طفل ولاعب جولف
one of the things that really sort of seeped into my pores,
من الاشياء التي تسربت الى عبر مساماتي
that I sort of lived my whole life, is process.
والتي عشت حياتي من اجلها
And it's the process of learning things.
هي عملية تعلم الاشياء.
One of the great things was that my father was an avid golfer, but he was lefty.
وكان من بين الاشياء العظيمة ان والدي كان متعطشاً للعبة الجولف, ولكنه كان أعسر
And he had a real passion for golf,
ولديه شغف حقيقي للجولف
and he also created this whole mythology
وهو من أوجد هذه الاسطورة
about Ben Hogan and various things.
حول بن هوجن والعديد من الاشياء.
Well, I learned a lot about interesting things
حسناً, لقد تعلمت الكثير من الاشياء الممتعة
that I knew nothing about at the time, but grew to know stuff about.
التي لم أكن اعرف عنها شيء, ونشأت لاعرف الكثير عنها.
And that was the mythology of skill.
وتلك هي اسطورة المهارة .
So, one of the things that I love to do is to explore skill.
وأحد الاشياء التي أحب فعلها , هو اكتشاف المهارة
And since Richard put me on this whole thing with music --
وحالما يضع ريتشارد الموسيقى
I'm supposed to actually be doing a project with Tod Machover
من المفترض فعلياً ان ابدأ المشروع مع تود ماكوفر
with the MIT Media Lab -- it relates a lot to music.
مع معمل ماساتشوستس للتكنولوجيا وسائل الإعلام
But Tod couldn't come and the project is sort of somewhere,
ولكن تود لم يستطيع الحضور , والمشروع في مكان ما.
I'm not sure whether it's happening the way we thought, or not.
ولست متأكداً ان كان المشروع سيتم بالطريقة التي خططنا لها ام لا.
But I'm going to explore skill, and juggling,
ولكن سـ أكتشف مهاراتي وابدأ بقذف الكرات
and basically visual music, I guess.
واعتقد ستكون الموسيقى تصويرية.
OK, you can start the music, thanks.
حسناً, بامكانك ان تبدأ الموسيقى. شكراً.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thanks. Thank you. Now, juggling can be a lot of fun;
شكراً, شكراً لكم. قذف الكرات ممتع جداً
play with skill and play with space, play with rhythm.
ان تلعب بمهارة وبالمساحة المخصصة لك وان تتبع الايقاع.
And you can turn the mike on now. I'm going to do a couple of pieces.
بامكانك تشغيل المايكرفون , سـ اقوم بقذف الكرات بطريقة اخرى
I do a big piece in a triangle
سـ افعلها على شكل مثلث
and these are three sections from it.
وهناك ثلاث اقسام لفعلها
Part of the challenge was to try to understand rhythm and space
وجزء من التحدي محاولة استيعاب الايقاع والفراغ.
using not just my hands -- because a lot of juggling is hand-oriented --
وليس فقط باستخدام يدي, لانه عادة قذف الكرات تكون يدوية
but using the rhythm of my body and feet,
ولكن باستخدام ايقاع جسدي وقدمي.
and controlling the balls with my feet.
والتحكم بالكرات بقدمي.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thanks. Now, this next section was an attempt to explore space.
شكراً. والان القسم الثاني هو محاولة اكتشاف الفراغ.
You see, I think Richard said something about people that are against something.
اعتقد ان ريتشارد قال شيئاً عن الناس التي تكون ضد شيء ما.
Well, a lot of people think jugglers defy gravity or do stuff.
حسنا, يعتقد كثير من الناس أن قاذف الكرات يتحدى الجاذبية .
Well, I kind of, from my childhood and golf and all that,
ومن خلال طفولتي ولعبي لكرة الجولف ان هذا كله
it's a process of joining with forces.
عملية الانضمام للقوى
And so what I'd like to do is try to figure out
وما أود فعله هو محاولة اكتشاف
how to join with the space through the technique.
كيفية الانضمام للقوة مع الفراغ من خلال هذه التقنية
So juggling gravity -- up, down.
جاذبية القذف-- أعلى , أسفل
If you figure out what up and down really are,
واذا اكتشفتم ماهيه الارتفاع والسقوط
it's a complex physical set of skills
إنها مجموعه مركبة من المهارات البدنية.
to be able to throw a ball down and up and everything,
لتتمكن من رمي الكرة لاعلى ولاسفل
but then you add in sideways.
وبعدها ترميها في كل الجهات
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Now, I look at it somewhat as a way -- when you learn juggling
والان , انظر اليها بطريقة ما , عندما تتعلم رمي الكرات
what you learn is how to feel with your eyes, and see with your hands
يجب ان تتعلم ان تشعر من خلال عينيك وترى بيديك
because you're not looking at your hands,
لأنك لاتنظر الى يديك
you're looking at where the balls are or you're looking at the audience.
ولكنك تنظر الى الكرات او الى الجمهور.
So this next part is really a way of understanding space and rhythm,
لذلك الجزء الاخر هو بعيد جداً عن فهم الفراغ والايقاع
with the obvious reference to the feet,
مع الاشارة الواضحة الى القدمين
but it's also time -- where the feet were, where the balls were.
انه التوقيت , اين تكون القدمين واين تكون الكرات
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thanks. So, visual music: rhythm and complexity.
شكراً. الموسيقى التصويرية والايقاع والتعقيد.
I'm going to build towards complexity now.
وسـ اعقدها قليلاً الى الان
Juggling three balls is simple and normal.
قذف ثلاث كرات طبيعي وسهل
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Excuse me.
(اعذروني)
We're jugglers, OK. And remember, you're transposing,
نحن لاعبين قذف الكرات.حسناً وتذكر انك الناقل
you're getting into a subculture here.
كنت على وشك تعلم ثقافة اخرى هنا
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And juggling -- the balls cross and all that.
وبامكانك قذف الكرات بشكل متعاكس وكل ذلك
OK, if you keep them in their assigned paths you get parallel lines
حسنا, واذا ابقيتها في تمريرة واحده تحصل على خطوط متوازيرة
of different heights, but then hopefully even rhythm.
وبارتفاعات مختلفة ولكن على امل ان تبقى على الايقاع
And you can change the rhythm -- good, Michael.
وبامكانك تغيير الايقاع, احسنت مايكل.
You can change the rhythm, if you get out of the lights.
بامكانك تغيير الايقاع اذا ابتعدت عن الاضواء
OK? Change the rhythm, so it's even.
حسناً, حتى لو تغير الايقاع
Or you can go back and change the height. Now, skill.
بامكانك ايضا العودة وتغيير الارتفاع . الان انها مهارة
But you're boxed in, if you can only do it up and down that way.
واذا كنت لاتستطيع فعلها الى اعلى واسفل فـ افعلها على هذا النحو
So, you've got to go after the space down there.
فـ بامكانك فعلها على المساحة الارضية هناك
OK, then you've got to combine them,
ثم علي الجمع بينهما
because then you have the whole spatial palette in front of you.
لأنه لديك امامك المساحة الكافية لعمل ذلك
And then you get crazy.
ومن ثم سـ تجن .
(Applause)
(ضحك)
Now, I'm actually going to ask you to try something,
الان , سـ أطلب منكم محاولة شيء ما
so you've got to pay attention. Complexity:
لذلك يجب ان تعيروني اهتمامكم جيداً, التعقيد.
if you spend enough time doing something, time slows down
اذا كنت تقضي وقتاً كافياً لعمل شيء, سيبدأ الوقت بالتباطئ
or your skill increases, so your perceptions change.
او عندما تزيد مهارتك , تتغير تصوراتك الخاصة.
It's learning skills -- like being in a high-speed car crash.
وتعلم المهارات كـ التواجد في حادث سيارة عالية السرعة
Things slow down as you learn, as you learn, as you learn.
الاشياء سـ تبطئ حالما تتعلمها, وطالما انت تتعلم
You may not be able to affect it, it almost drifts on you. It goes.
ومن الممكن الا تكون قادراً على التأثير عليها, انها كالاكوام عليك
But that's the closest approximation I can have to it.
ولكن هذا أقرب تقريب من الممكن ان احصل عليه
So, complexity. Now, how many here are jugglers?
التعقيد. الان هل هنا من يلعب قذف الكرات؟
OK, so most of you are going to have a similar reaction to this.
حسناً. اذا الغالبية منكم سـ تكون لديها ردة الفعل نفسها.
OK? And whoever laughed there --
حسنا, ومن ضحك هنا
you understood it completely, right?
فهم ما افعله بالكامل, صحيح؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
No, it looks like a mess. It looks like a mess with a guy there,
لا, انها تشبة الفوضى. انها فوضى مع الرجل هناك
who's got his hands around that mess, OK.
الذي وضع يديه بتلك الفوضى, حسناً.
Well, that's what juggling is about, right?
هذا هو المقصود من قذف الكرات. صحيح؟
It's being able to do something that other people can't do or can't understand.
ان تكون قادراً على فعل اشياء , الاخرين لايقدرون على فعلها او حتى فهمها.
All right. So, that's one way of doing it, which is five balls down.
حسناً, هناك طريقة لفعلها وهي ان تسقط الكرات لاسفل
OK? Another way is the outside.
والطريقة الاخرى ان تقذفها للخارج
And you could play with the rhythm.
وبإمكانك ان تلعب مع الايقاع.
Same pattern.
على نفس النمط.
Make it faster and smaller.
اجعلها أسرع واصغر.
Make it wider.
اجعلها أوسع.
Make it narrower.
وأضيق
Bring it back up.
وأعيدها لاعلى.
OK. It's done. Thanks.
حسنا, انتهت. شكراً
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Now, what I wanted to get to is that you're all very bright, very tactile.
والان, مااريد الوصول اليه هو انكم جميعكم حسيين
I have no idea how computer-oriented or three-dimensionally-oriented you are,
ليس لدي ادنى فكرة ....
but let's try something.
دعونا نجرب شيء
OK, so since you all don't understand what the five-ball pattern is,
حيث انكم لم تفهمو نمط الكرات الخمس
I'm going to give you a little clue.
سـ اعطيكم تلميحاً بسيطاً
Enough of a clue? So, you get the pattern, right? OK.
هل يكفي هذا التلميح؟ فهمتم النمط صحيح؟ حسنا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
You're not getting off that easy. All right?
لن تتعلموها بتلك السهولة, اليس كذلك؟
Now, do me a favor: follow the ball that I ask you to follow.
الان, اسدو الي معروفا. اتبعو الكره التي اطلب منكم ان تتبعوها.
Green.
الكرة الخضراء
Yellow.
الصفراء
Pink.
الوردية
White.
البيضاء
OK, you can do that? Yeah? OK.
حسناً, استطعتم معرفه نمط الكرات, اليس كذلك؟
Now, let's actually learn something.
الان دعونا نتعلم فعليا شيء اخر
Actually, let me put you in that area of learning, which is very insecure.
في الواقع , دعوني اضعكم في مكان المتعلم وهي امنة جداً
You want to do it? Yeah? OK.
تريدون فعل ذلك, صحيح؟ حسناً
Hands out in front of you. Palms up, together.
ضعو ايديكم امامكم افردوها بجانب بعضها
What you're going to learn is this.
ماانتم على وشك تعلمه هو هذا
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
OK? So what I want you to do is just listen to me and do it.
لذلك ما اريدكم ان تفعلوه هو تستمعو لي جيداً وتحاولو فعله
Index finger, middle finger, ring, little.
السبابة الاوسط بنصر خنصر
Little, ring, middle, index. And then open.
خنصر بنصر الاوسط السبابة ومن ثم افتحوها
Finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger.
اصبع ,اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع , اصبع
A little bit faster.
اسرع قليلاً.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
All right. A lot of different learning processes going on in here.
حسناً, كثير من طرق التعلم تحصل هنا
One learning process that I see is this --
ومن طرق التعلم التي رأيتها هي هذة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
OK. Another learning process that I see is this --
حسناً, طريقة اخرى للتعلم هي هذه
OK. So, everybody take a deep breath in, breath out. OK.
حسناً, نفس عميق شهيق زفير
Now, one more time, and --
الان مرة اخرى و
finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger. Open.
اصبع ,اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع , اصبع افتح
Finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger. OK.
اصبع ,اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع , اصبع
Shake your hands out.
هزو ايديكم
Now, I assume a lot of you spend a lot of time at a computer.
الان , اعتقد ان كثيراً منكم يقضون وقتا طويلاً على الحاسب؟
OK? So, what you're doing is, you're going la, la, la,
اذن ماتفعلوه هو انكم تكتبون
and you're getting this. OK?
وتشاهدون الشاشة حسنا؟
So that's exactly what I'm going to ask you to do,
وهذا بالضبط ما أريدكم ان تفعلوه
but in a slightly different way. You're going to combine it.
ولكن بطريقة مختلفة قليلاً , ولكن بدمجها
So what I want you to do is -- fingers.
وما اريدكم ان تفعلوه هو الاصابع
I'll tell you what to do with your fingers, same thing.
سـ اخبركم ان تفعلو باصابعكم الشيء نفسه
But I want you to do is also, with your eyes,
وايضاً ان تفعلو شيء اخر باعينكم
is follow the colored ball that I ask you to follow.
وهو ان تتبعو الكره الملونة التي اطلب منكم متابعتها
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
OK? Here we go.
حسناً, ها نحن
So, we're going to start off looking at the white ball --
سـ نبداً بمتابعة الكرة البيضاء.
and I'm going to tell you which color,
ومن ثم سـ أخبركم اي كره سـ تتبعون
and I'm also going to tell you to go with your fingers. OK?
وايضا ان تحركو اصابعكم, اتفقنا؟
So white ball and --
اذن, الكره البيضاء و
finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger. Pink.
اصبع ,اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع , اصبع . الوردية
Finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger. Green.
اصبع ,اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع , اصبع. الخضراء
Finger, finger, finger, finger. Yellow.
اصبع اصبع اصبع اصبع , الصفراء
Finger, finger, finger, pink or finger.
اصبع ,اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, الوردية او اصبع
Pink, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger, finger.
الوردية.اصبع ,اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع, اصبع , اصبع
All right.
حسناً.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
How did you do? Well? OK. The reason I wanted you to do this is
ما فعلتم؟ جيد؟ حسناً السبب الذي جعلتكم تفعلون هذا هو
because that's actually what most people face throughout their lives,
ان هذا فعلا هو مايواجهة الكثير من الناس في حياتهم
a moment of learning, a moment of challenge.
لحظة تعلم, ولحظة تحدي
It's a moment that you can't make sense of.
اللحظة التي لاتشعر بها بشيء
Why the hell should I learn this? OK?
لماذا يجب ان اتعلم هذا؟ حسنا؟
Does it really have anything to do with anything in my life?
هل فعلاً له علاقة بشيء يحدث في حياتي؟
You know, I can't decipher -- is it fun? Is it challenging? Am I supposed to cheat?
اتعلم, لا استطيع حله, هل هو ممتع؟ هل هو تحدي؟ هل بامكاني الغش؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
You know, what are you supposed to do?
هل تعلم ماعليك فعله؟
You've got somebody up here who is the operative principle
لديكم شخص هنا
of doing that for his whole life. OK?
قضى حياته في فعل ذلك .
Trying to figure that stuff out. But is it going to get you anywhere?
لمحاولة اكتشاف تلك الاشياء, ولكن هل ستفيدكم على أي حال؟
It's just a moment. That's all it is, a moment. OK?
هي لحظة, مجرد لحظة فقط.
I'm going to change the script for one second. Just let me do this.
سـ احاول ان اغير النص لثانية واحدة فقط, اسمحو لي
I don't need music for it. Talking about time in a moment.
لا احتاج موسيقى لفعلها. الحديث عن الوقت في اللحظة
There's a piece that I recently developed which was all about that,
هناك قطعة طورتها مؤخراً , وكان كل شيء حولها
a moment. And what I do as a creative artist
لـ لحظة. ومافعلته كـ فنان مبدع
is I develop vocabularies or languages of moving objects.
هو اني طورت مفردات ولغات حركة الاجسام
What I've done for you here, I developed a lot of those tricks
ومافعلته لكم هنا, هو اني طورت العديد من الخدع
and I put the choreography together,
ووضعت معها فن الرقص
but they're not original techniques.
ولكن تلك ليست المهارات الاصلية
Now, I'm going to start showing you some original techniques
الان, سأريكم بعض المهارات الاصلية
that come from the work that I've developed. OK?
التي طورت منها مهاراتي , حسنا
So, a moment, how would you define a moment?
لحظة, كيف يمكن ان تعرف اللحظة؟
Well, as a juggler, what I wanted to do was create something
حسناً, كـ قاذف للكرات ما اردت فعله هو انا اصنع شيئاً.
that was representational of a moment.
وكانت تلك تمثيلية اللحظة
Ahhh.
اااااااااااه
All right, I'm going to get on my knees and do it.
حسناً, سـ أركع على ركبتاي وافعله
So, a moment.
لحظة
(Rattling)
خرخشة
OK? And then, what I did as a juggler was say,
حسناً, ماذا كنت اقول كـ قاذف للكرات
OK, what can I do to make that something
ماذا يمكنني فعله لاجعل ذلك الشيء
that is dependent on something else, another dynamic.
يعتمد على شيء اخر وحيوي اكثر
(Rattling)
(خرخشة)
So, a moment.
لحظة
Another moment.
لحظة اخرى
(Rattling)
(خرخشة)
Excuse me, still getting there. A moment that travels.
اعذروني, مازلت احاول. لحظة الانتقال
A moment -- no, we'll try that again. It separates, and comes back together.
لحظة, لا. سـ اعيد تجربتها من جديد. تنفصل وتعود لبعضها مرة اخرى.
Time. How can you look at time?
الوقت, كيف يمكنك ان تنظر للوقت؟
And what do you dedicate it to, in exploring a particular thing?
وكيف يمكنك ان تخصصه لاكتشاف شيء معين
Well, obviously, there's something in here,
حسناً, يوجد هنا شيء ما
and you can all have a guess as to what it is.
وبامكانكم ان تخمنو ماهو هذا الشيء
There's a mystery. There's a mystery in the moment.
هناك لغز. هناك لغز في اللحظة
And it has to settle. And then it's dependent on something else.
ويجب ان يستوي ومن ثم يعتمد على شيء اخر
And then it comes to rest. Just a little thing about time.
بووف انها تأتي للراحة فقط شيء بسيط بالنسبة للتوقيت
Now, this has expanded into a much bigger piece,
الان, توسعت هذه كثيراً في قطعة اكبر بكثير
because I use ramps of different parabolas that I roll the balls on
لاني استخدمت السلال المتكافئة ولففتها على الكرات
while I'm keeping time with this.
بينما انا احفظ الوقت مع هذه
But I just thought I'd talk about a moment.
ولكني فكرت اني اريد ان اتحدث عنها للحظة
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
All right. OK. Can we show the video of the triangle?
حسناً, هل بامكاننا عرض مقطع المثلث؟
Are we ready to do that? Yes?
هل نحن جاهزون لعرضه؟ نعم
This is the piece that I told you about.
هذا هو المقطع الذي اخبرتكم عنه
It's a much bigger piece that I do exploring the space of a geometric triangle.
انها قطعة اكبر بكثير كـ مثلث هندسي من المساحة هنا
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thanks. The only thing I'll say about the last session is,
شكراً. الشيء الوحيد الذي سـ اقوله بشأن المشهد الاخير هو
you ever try juggling and driving the car with your knees
هل حاولت ان تقذف الكرات وتقود السيارة بركبتيك
at 120 miles an hour?
بسرعة عشرين ميلا في الساعه؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The only other thing is, it was a real shock.
الشيء الاخر كان صدمة حقيقية,
I always drove motorcycles. And when I bought my first car, it shocked me
اعتدت دائما ان اقود الدراجة. وعندما اشتريت سيارتي الاولى
that it cost three times more than my parents' house. Interesting.
صدمت بانها كلفتني اكثر بثلاث مرات من منزل والديّ. مثير للاهتمام
Anyway, balance:
على أي حال, التوازن..
constant movement to find an approach to stillness.
حركة ثابتة للوصول الى السكون
Cheating.
غش
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Balance: making up the rules so you can't cheat,
توازن, افعلها بطريقة اخرى حتى لاتتمكن من الغش
so you learn to approach stillness with different parts of your body.
اذن تعلمت ان تصل الى السكون بطرق مختلفة باستخدام جسدك
To have a conversation with it. To speak. To listen.
لاجراء محادثة معه, لتتحدث وتسمع
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Hup. Now, it's dependent on rhythm,
الان هيه تعتمد على الايقاع
and keeping a center of balance. When it falls, going underneath.
وتحافظ على مركز التوازن عندما تسقط .
So, there's a rhythm to it.
لذلك هي لها ايقاع
The rhythm can get much smaller.
والايقاع ممكن ان يكون اصغر بكثير
As your skill increases, you learn to find those tinier spaces,
وبزيادة مهارتك بامكانك التعلم كيف تجد تلك الفراغات الاصغر
those tinier movements. Thanks.
وتلك الحركات الصغيرة, شكراً.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Now, I'm going to show you the beginnings of a piece
الان , سأريكم البداية بـ قطعة
that is about balance in some ways, and also --
تريكم التوازن باشكال مختلفة
oh, actually, if you're bored, not here, here's one use for it.
اوه, اذا كنت ضجران - ليس هنا- هذة مفيدة لك
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
You can go with the "Sticks One" music.
بامكانك ان تلعب بالعصي وموسيقى واحدة
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thanks. That has a certain kind of balance to it, which is all about plumb.
شكراً. كان هذا نوع مؤكد عن التوازن وكله عن التوازن العمودي
I apprenticed with a carpenter and learned about plumb, square and level.
تدربت مع نجاراً, وعرفت عن المربع والمستوى العمودي
And they influenced that, and this next piece, which I'll do a little segment of.
وتأثرت بالقطعة المقبلة والتي سـ اعمل على تقطيعها !
"Two Sticks," you can go with it. Thanks.
عصايتين, بامكانك تشغيل الموسيقى. شكراً.
Which is again exploring space, or the lines in space.
واللتين سـ تكتشفان المساحة او الخطوط الموجودة في المساحة
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Working with space and the lines in space in a different way.
اللعب بهما بالمسافة وفي خطوط المسافة في طرق عدة
Oh, let's see here.
لنرى هنا
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So, I'll come back to that in a second. But working with one ball,
سـ اعود لتلك بعد ثواني ولكن فقط بكره واحدة
now, what if you attach something to it, or change it.
والان, ماذا لو الصقناها بشيء اخر او استبدلناها.
This is a little thing that I made
هذا شيء بسيط صنعته
because I really like the idea of curves and balls together.
لأني أحب فكرة المنحنيات والكرات سوياً
And then creating space and the rhythm of space,
وبعدها خلق مساحة وايقاع للمساحة
using the surface of the balls, the surface of the arms.
باسخدام سطح الكرات وسطح الساعد
Just a little toy. Which leads me to the next thing,
انها لعبة صغيرة, والتي ارشدتني للشيء التالي
which is --
وهو
what have I got here? OK. All right.
ماذا لدي هنا؟ حسنا
I'm actually leading up to something,
انا فعلياً اخطط لشيء ما
the newest thing that I'm working on. This is not it.
الشيء الأحدث الذي اعمل عليه , ليس هذا
This is exploring geometry and the rhythm of shape.
هذا هو استكشاف هندسة وايقاع الشكل
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Now, what I just did was I worked with the mathematics --
الان, مافعلته هو انني تعاملت مع الرياضيات
the diameter and the circumference.
قطر الدائرة ومحيطها
Sometimes these pieces are mathematical, in that way
احيانا, تكون هذه القطع الرياضية بهذا الشكل
that I look at a shape and say, what about if I use this and this and this.
ان انظر الى شكل ما واقول ماذا سـ يحدث لو استخدمت هذا وهذا وهذا
Sometimes what happens in life affects my choice
احيانا مايحدث في الحياة يؤثر على خياري.
of objects that I try to work with.
في الاشياء التي سـ استخدمها
The next piece that I'm going to do -- which is the cylinders piece,
القطعة التالية التي سـ استخدمها هي الاسطوانات
if you want to get that up --
اذا كنت تود الحصول عليها
it has to do with cylinder seals from about 5,000 years ago,
كانت مع الاختام الاسطوانية منذ مايقرب 5000 سنة
which were stones with designs that were used to roll over wet clay
مصممة من الحجارة التي كانت تمرر على الطين الرطب
with all sorts of great designs. I love ceramics and all of that.
وبجميع انواع التصاميم العظيمة, أحب السيراميك وكل تلك المواد
It's a combination of that, the beauty of that, the shape,
انها مزيح من ذلك في جمالها وشكلها
and the stories that were involved in it,
وبكل القصص المرتبطة بها
as well as the fact that they protected the contents.
فضلاَ عن حقيقة انها تحمي محتوياتها
The second influence on this piece came from recycling
والتأثير الثاني على هذه القطعة كان من اعادة التدوير
and looking into a tin can recycling bin
والبحث في طريقة اعادة تدوير القصدير
and seeing all that beautiful emptiness.
وترى تلك الفراغات الجميلة التي بداخلها
So, if you want to go with the music for cylinders.
لذلك من فضلك موسيقى الاسطوانات
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Talking about geometry and everything,
بالتحدث عن علم الهندسة وكل شيء
if you take the circle and you split it in half --
اذا اخذت دائرة وفصلتها الى جزئين
can you run "S-Curve music?"
هل بامكانك تشغيل موسيقى انحناءة حرف الـ اس
I'm going to do just a short version of it.
سـ افعل نسخة بسيطة منه
Circles split in half and rotated, and mythology.
تقسيم الدائرة الى قسمين واستدارتها هي الاسطورة.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Anyway, that piece also has a kinetic sculpture in the middle of it,
على أي حال, يوجد في منتصفها قطعة النحت
and I dance around a small stage so --
وانا ارقص حول مسرح صغير
two minutes, just to end? The latest piece that I'm working on --
دقيقتين فقط للنهاية؟ اخر قطعة عملت عليها
what I love is that I never know what I'm working on, why I'm working on it.
ما أحبه هو انني لا اعرف على ماذا سـ اعمل بعد, او لماذا اعمل عليها
They're not ideas, they're instincts.
ليس هناك أي فكرة, هناك الغرائز فقط
And the latest thing that I'm working on --
واخر قطعة عملت عليها
(Clattering) --
(ضوضاء)
is something really -- I don't know what it is yet.
هو شيء فعلاً, لا ادري ماهو بعد
And that's good. I like not to know for as long as possible.
وهذا شيء جيد, لا أريد ان اعرف ماهو لاطول وقت ممكن
Well, because then it tells me the truth,
لانه سـ يخبرني الحقيقه لو عرفت ماهو
instead of me imposing the truth.
بدلاً من فرضي للحقيقة
And what it is, is working with both positive and negative space
وهو يتعامل مع كلا الناحيتين الموجبة والسالبة
but also with these curves.
ولكن ايضا مع تلك المنحنيات
And what it involves,
ومايتداخل بهما
and I don't know if my hands are too beaten up to do it or not,
ولا اعلم ان كانت يدي مفروض عليهما ان يفعلان ذلك ام لا
but I'll do a little bit of it.
ولكن سـ افعل القليل بهما
It initially started off with me stacking these things,
والبداية برصهما جنبا الى جنب
bunches of them, and then playing with the sense of space,
اجمعها سوية ثم العب بهما مع الشعور بالمساحة
of filling in the space. And then it started changing,
لتعبئة الفراغ وتبدأ بالتغيير من جديد
and become folding on themselves.
وسـ ينطون على انفسهم
And then changing levels.
ثم اغير المستويات
Because my attempt is to make visual instruments,
لان محاولتي هي جعل الادوات مرئية
not to just make -- I'll try one other thing.
ليس فقط لفعل...سـ أحاول تجربة واحدة اخرى
For work in three dimensions, with your perceptions of space and time.
للعمل على ثلاث ابعاد, مع تصوراتك بالنسبة للمساحة والوقت
Now, I don't know exactly where it's going,
الان, لا ادري فعلا الى ماذا ستنتهي
but I've got a bit of effort involved in this thing.
ولكن لدي القليل من الجهد على هذا الشيء
And it's going to change as I go through it.
وهو سـ يتغير حالما اغيره
But I really like it, it feels right.
ولكني فعلا أحبه, يبدو صحيحا.
This may not be the right shape, and -- look at this shape,
ربما هذا ليس الشكل الصحيح , وسـ انظر لهذا الشكل
and then I'll show you the first design I ever put to it,
ومن ثم سـ اريكم تصميمي الأول الذي وضعته عليه
just to see, just to play,
فقط لرؤيته واللعب به
because I love all different kinds of things to play with.
لأني أحب جميع الاشكال المختلفة التي ألعب بها
Let's see here.
دعونا نرى هنا
To work with the positive and negative in a different way.
للعب بالموجب والسالب في طرق مختلفة
And to change, and to change.
ولتغييرها وتغييرها
So, I'm off in my new direction with this to explore rhythm and space.
لذا سـ انتهي في خطتي القادمة لاكتشاف الايقاع والمساحة
We'll see what I come up with. Thanks for having me.
سـ نرى لاحقا مايمكنني فعله. شكراً لاستضافتي.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)